{
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "The post-independence Nigerian economy has been characterized by ________",
        "options": [
          "a. Pro-imperialism",
          "b. Neo-colonial capitalism",
          "c. Independent capitalism",
          "d. Expatriate domination",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Neo-colonial capitalism",
        "id": 1
      },
      {
        "question": "The goal of national development is to _______",
        "options": [
          "a. Improve the living conditions of the citizenry",
          "b. Provide employment",
          "c. Fight corruption",
          "d. Achieve economic growth"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Improve the living conditions of the citizenry",
        "id": 2
      },
      {
        "question": "Nigeria was introduced into the world capitalist system during the ______ economy.",
        "options": [
          "a. Independence",
          "b. Pre-colonial",
          "c. Post-independence",
          "d. Colonial"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Colonial",
        "id": 3
      },
      {
        "question": "NEEDS _______ document stated that Nigeria had one of the weakest economies in the world",
        "options": [
          "a. 2003",
          "b. 2004",
          "c. 2005",
          "d. 2006"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. 2004",
        "id": 4
      },
      {
        "question": "There is the persistence of the _______ rather than the productive nature of the economy.",
        "options": [
          "a. Interventionist",
          "b. Imperialist",
          "c. Mercantilist",
          "d. Capitalist"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Mercantilist",
        "id": 5
      },
      {
        "question": "Massive plundering of Nigeria's economic resources was initially carried out by _____",
        "options": [
          "a. Nigerians",
          "b. Imperialist",
          "c. British",
          "d. Ruling Class"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. British",
        "id": 6
      },
      {
        "question": "________ and ________ blocked the way for natural and gradual capitalist development in Nigeria.",
        "options": [
          "a. Imperialism and capitalism",
          "b. Colonialism and capitalism",
          "c. Capitalism and domination",
          "d. Interventionism and capitalism"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Colonialism and capitalism",
        "id": 7
      },
      {
        "question": "Nigeria has adopted _______ development plans since independence?",
        "options": [
          "a. 4",
          "b. 5",
          "c. 6",
          "d. 9"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. 9",
        "id": 8
      },
      {
        "question": "Pre-capitalist Nigerian economy thrived on barter and ___________",
        "options": [
          "a. Reciprocity",
          "b. Subsistence",
          "c. Agriculture",
          "d. Trade"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Trade",
        "id": 9
      },
      {
        "question": "Traditional Nigerian economy was marked by division of labour according to _____and",
        "options": [
          "a. Sex, background",
          "b. Age, lineage",
          "c. Age, sex",
          "d. Sex, kingroup"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Age, sex",
        "id": 10
      },
      {
        "question": "Post-independence economy is not remarkably different from the__________ economy.",
        "options": [
          "a. Colonial",
          "b. Pre-colonial",
          "c. Independence",
          "d. Traditional"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Colonial",
        "id": 11
      },
      {
        "question": "The mainstay of the traditional Nigerian economy was_________",
        "options": [
          "a. Trading",
          "b. Oil",
          "c. Agriculture",
          "d. Production"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Oil",
        "id": 12
      },
      {
        "question": "All except one is not a marker of a strong, healthy and viable economy",
        "options": [
          "a. High GDP",
          "b. Low exchange rate",
          "c. Increase in per capita income",
          "d. Reduction in inflation rate"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Low exchange rate",
        "id": 13
      },
      {
        "question": "The annual GDP and the driver of economic growth as at 2014 were _______ and _____",
        "options": [
          "a. 6.2%; oil sector",
          "b. 6.2%; agriculture",
          "c. 6.3%; oil sector",
          "d. 6.3%; non-oil sector"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. 6.3%; non-oil sector",
        "id": 14
      },
      {
        "question": "______ is the bedrock of any form of contemporary human organization.",
        "options": [
          "a. Polity",
          "b. Society",
          "c. Economy",
          "d. Religion"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Society",
        "id": 15
      },
      {
        "question": "Ownership of the means of production in traditional Hausa-Fulani empire was --------",
        "options": [
          "a. Communal",
          "b. Feudal",
          "c. Individual",
          "d. Cooperative"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Feudal",
        "id": 16
      },
      {
        "question": "The British handed over power to the London-groomed",
        "options": [
          "a. Pro-imperialists",
          "b. Bourgeoisie",
          "c. Imperialists",
          "d. Capitalists"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Pro-imperialists",
        "id": 17
      },
      {
        "question": "One of these represents 'Flag independence' represents",
        "options": [
          "a. Economic independence",
          "b. Sovereignty",
          "c. Political independence",
          "d. Foreign control"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Foreign control",
        "id": 18
      },
      {
        "question": "______ assessed Nigerian economy as the first and biggest in Africa in 2014.",
        "options": [
          "a. IMF",
          "b. World Bank",
          "c. ADB",
          "d. Paris Club"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. World Bank",
        "id": 19
      },
      {
        "question": "Nigeria was incorporated into the international capitalist framework through",
        "options": [
          "a. Taxation",
          "b. Exchange",
          "c. Peasantry",
          "d. Production"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Taxation",
        "id": 20
      },
      {
        "question": "Nigeria is dependent on ____ for consolidated budgetary revenues",
        "options": [
          "a. Production export",
          "b. Service export",
          "c. Resource export",
          "d. Goods import"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Service export",
        "id": 21
      },
      {
        "question": "A consequence of the liberal nature of the Nigeria market is______",
        "options": [
          "a. Embracement of agricultural biotechnology for GMO's",
          "b. Poverty",
          "c. Insecurity",
          "d. Privatization"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Embracement of agricultural biotechnology for GMO's",
        "id": 22
      },
      {
        "question": "Corruption and _____ have further crippled the economy and national development",
        "options": [
          "a. Economic depression",
          "b. Over dependence on oil",
          "c. Resource control",
          "d. Globalization"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Over dependence on oil",
        "id": 23
      },
      {
        "question": "The imperialistic underdevelopment of Nigeria was instituted during trade with the __",
        "options": [
          "a. America",
          "b. France",
          "c. Portugal",
          "d. West"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. West",
        "id": 24
      },
      {
        "question": "Africa was partitioned at the Berlin Conference of _________",
        "options": [
          "a. 1854",
          "b. 1855",
          "c. 1856",
          "d. 1858"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. 1854",
        "id": 25
      },
      {
        "question": "The focal point of every health care system is to provide ------------ for the prevention of diseases as well as to treat ill person suffering from HIV/AIDS and Ebola virus.",
        "options": [
          "a. Information",
          "b. Directive",
          "c. Health services",
          "d. Complementary medicine"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Health services",
        "id": 26
      },
      {
        "question": "Health care Delivery system (HCDS) can be described as all the formal and non-formal activities which in the provision of health services to _________",
        "options": [
          "a. A patient",
          "b. Mothers",
          "c. Children",
          "d. A Population"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. A Population",
        "id": 27
      },
      {
        "question": "The definition of HCDS is __________; hence it covers all health care practices and services that serve the public health.",
        "options": [
          "a. Fragmented",
          "b. Holistic",
          "c. Proper",
          "d. Good"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Holistic",
        "id": 28
      },
      {
        "question": "HCDS is classified into orthodox health care, indigenous health care and _______",
        "options": [
          "a. Traditional health care",
          "b. Primary health care (PHC)",
          "c. Western health care",
          "d. Complementary health care"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Western health care",
        "id": 29
      },
      {
        "question": "Orthodox health care delivery system (OHCDS) delivers health services to people through its ____________ components in Nigeria.",
        "options": [
          "a. Two",
          "b. Four",
          "c. Three",
          "d. Western and indigenous medicine"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Three",
        "id": 30
      },
      {
        "question": "The OHCDS has a______________ as a team leader.",
        "options": [
          "a. Health professional",
          "b. Pharmacy",
          "c. Doctor",
          "d. Nurse"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Pharmacy",
        "id": 31
      },
      {
        "question": "Tertiary Health care which is at the _________of the national health system consists of highly specialized services in Nigeria.",
        "options": [
          "a. Level",
          "b. Management",
          "c. Good",
          "d. Apex"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Apex",
        "id": 32
      },
      {
        "question": "Lucas and Gilles (2003) see primary health care in Nigeria as a _________ health care that is community-based",
        "options": [
          "a. Proper",
          "b. Good",
          "c. Unique",
          "d. Defined"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Good",
        "id": 33
      },
      {
        "question": "PHC brings health care as close as possible where the __________live and work.",
        "options": [
          "a. Patients",
          "b. Recovered patients",
          "c. Workers",
          "d. People"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. People",
        "id": 34
      },
      {
        "question": "The indigenous medicine, in the following words as _________ of the prevention and care of diseases in Nigeria.",
        "options": [
          "a. Traditional art or culture",
          "b. Traditional art or science",
          "c. Traditional art and culture",
          "d. Cultural ways"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Traditional art or science",
        "id": 35
      },
      {
        "question": "A herbalist is a man or _______ of plants.",
        "options": [
          "a. Woman",
          "b. Worker",
          "c. Professional",
          "d. Elder"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Woman",
        "id": 36
      },
      {
        "question": "The bone setters use locally woven splint to help properly ________simple, compound and complex fractured bones for patients' quick recuperation",
        "options": [
          "a. Put",
          "b. Care",
          "c. Align",
          "d. Splint"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Align",
        "id": 37
      },
      {
        "question": "A herbalist uses the following except_____in treating patients.",
        "options": [
          "a. Leaves",
          "b. Banks",
          "c. Roots",
          "d. Mud leaves"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Mud leaves",
        "id": 38
      },
      {
        "question": "Acupressure is using needles to locate the _________",
        "options": [
          "a. Acu --- area",
          "b. Acu --- body",
          "c. Acu --- nerves",
          "d. Acu ---- point"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Acu --- body",
        "id": 39
      },
      {
        "question": "Acupuncture is using needles to locate the _______, so that pain messages can be halted from reaching the brain of the sick.",
        "options": [
          "a. Brain",
          "b. Body",
          "c. Meridian",
          "d. Brain messages"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Meridian",
        "id": 40
      },
      {
        "question": "Alexander technique is using correct posture so that the body is able to function naturally and with the minimum amount of ________ effort.",
        "options": [
          "a. Body",
          "b. Strength",
          "c. Muscular",
          "d. Movement"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Strength",
        "id": 41
      },
      {
        "question": "AIDS may mean a group of signs and symptoms resulting from an acquired virus that reduces or makes the body immunity inactive or deficient and thus exposes the patient to___________ that may lead to his or her death.",
        "options": [
          "a. Diseases",
          "b. Diseases and illnesses",
          "c. Opportunistic infections",
          "d. Sore"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Opportunistic infections",
        "id": 42
      },
      {
        "question": "The first HIV/AIDS incident in Nigeria was in the ___________ and this led to serious threats to Nigerians.",
        "options": [
          "a. 1970s",
          "b. 1980s",
          "c. 1990s",
          "d. 2000s"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. 1980s",
        "id": 43
      },
      {
        "question": "Ebola virus first appeared in __________ in simultaneous outbreaks in Africa.",
        "options": [
          "a. 1940",
          "b. 1966",
          "c. 1976",
          "d. 1975"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. 1976",
        "id": 44
      },
      {
        "question": "The simultaneous outbreaks were in ___________and _____________",
        "options": [
          "a. Nkata, in Sudan and Yamtutu in Democratic Republic (DR) of Congo",
          "b. Akata, in Sudan and Yama in DR of Congo",
          "c. Nzara in Sudan and Yalele in DR of Congo",
          "d. Nzara in Sudan and Yambuku in Dr Congo"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Nzara in Sudan and Yambuku in Dr Congo",
        "id": 45
      },
      {
        "question": "For the treatment of HIV/AIDS, anti-retroviral drugs (ARVDs) have been found to be useful ________to the lives of the infected persons",
        "options": [
          "a. Treat",
          "b. Care",
          "c. Secure",
          "d. Prolong"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Prolong",
        "id": 46
      },
      {
        "question": "ARVDs reduce the viral loads of HIV in patients to ______________",
        "options": [
          "a. 5%",
          "b. 10%",
          "c. 0.01%",
          "d. Zero level"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Zero level",
        "id": 47
      },
      {
        "question": "DNA vaccines are some of the vaccines used in the treatment of ____________ patients.",
        "options": [
          "a. HIV/AIDS",
          "b. Lassa fever",
          "c. HIV/AIDS and cancer",
          "d. Ebola virus"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Ebola virus",
        "id": 48
      },
      {
        "question": "Ebola virus may lead to the infection of the practitioner and those in the_______",
        "options": [
          "a. Family",
          "b. Community",
          "c. Workplace",
          "d. Immediate environment"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Immediate environment",
        "id": 49
      },
      {
        "question": "Homeopathy, in particular, has a lot to offer and is known to cure many diseases that 24/61 are otherwise labeled as ____________ by modern medicine.",
        "options": [
          "a. Curable",
          "b. Incurable",
          "c. Manageable",
          "d. Preventable"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Incurable",
        "id": 50
      },
      {
        "question": "The three environmental regions of the eastern and southern cultural zones include all of the following EXCEPT _________",
        "options": [
          "a. Coastal wetlands",
          "b. Savannah",
          "c. Tropical forest",
          "d. Coastal hotland"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Coastal hotland",
        "id": 51
      },
      {
        "question": "The phenomenon of judging one's culture as superior to another culture is called ______",
        "options": [
          "a. Cultural subjectivism",
          "b. Cultural relativism",
          "c. Ethnicity",
          "d. Ethnocentrism"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Ethnocentrism",
        "id": 52
      },
      {
        "question": "Cultural zones are _________ areas occupied by individuals or groups who share common cultural traits.",
        "options": [
          "a. Historical",
          "b. Agricultural",
          "c. Religious",
          "d. Geographical"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Geographical",
        "id": 53
      },
      {
        "question": "The eastern cultural zone consists of ________ states",
        "options": [
          "a. Four",
          "b. Six",
          "c. Eight",
          "d. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. All of the above",
        "id": 54
      },
      {
        "question": "All except one of the towns below is a major city in the eastern cultural zone",
        "options": [
          "a. Owerri",
          "b. Enugu",
          "c. Port Harcourt",
          "d. Onitsha",
          "e. Umuahia"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Port Harcourt",
        "id": 55
      },
      {
        "question": "The eastern cultural zone is",
        "options": [
          "a. Homogenous in History but not in culture and language",
          "b. Homogenous in language but not in culture",
          "c. Homogenous in culture but not in history",
          "d. Homogenous in language but not in history",
          "e. Homogenous in language, culture, and history"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "e. Homogenous in language, culture, and history",
        "id": 56
      },
      {
        "question": "All except one of the statements below is true of the southern cultural zone.",
        "options": [
          "a. The cultural heritage of the southern zone is similar but not homogenous in Origin and history",
          "b. The six states are located at the Point where the River Niger joins the Atlantic Ocean via the Gulf of Guinea",
          "c. The zone is a source of the economic mainstay of the Nigerian economy.",
          "d. Violence and youth restiveness are absent in this zone",
          "e. The area has great potential for tourism and agriculture"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Violence and youth restiveness are absent in this zone",
        "id": 57
      },
      {
        "question": "Gender discrimination is prevalent in the eastern and southern cultural zones of Nigerian because of:",
        "options": [
          "a. Division of labour by gender",
          "b. Improvement in women education",
          "c. Domination of men over women",
          "d. Nigeria is a signatory to the international convention on equality for women."
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Nigeria is a signatory to the international convention on equality for women.",
        "id": 58
      },
      {
        "question": "All except one reason below is given by Christian husbands for disobeying the biblical injunction of marriage to one wife in the eastern and southern cultural zones.",
        "options": [
          "a. Barrenness",
          "b. Sexual dissatisfaction",
          "c. Sexual promiscuity",
          "d. Excessive love of their wife",
          "e. Delivery of only one set of children (Male or Female)"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Sexual promiscuity",
        "id": 59
      },
      {
        "question": "Mother and the newly born baby are allowed to stay close for sometimes after delivery in the eastern and southern cultural zones of Nigeria for:",
        "options": [
          "a. Proper discussion",
          "b. Proper understanding",
          "c. Proper bonding",
          "d. Proper proximity",
          "e. Proper greeting."
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Proper bonding",
        "id": 60
      },
      {
        "question": "Another name for the specific evolutionary theory of culture is",
        "options": [
          "a. Darwinism",
          "b. Boasinanism",
          "c. None of the above",
          "d. Evolutionism"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Darwinism",
        "id": 61
      },
      {
        "question": "Is it true that symbols are learned through skill education?",
        "options": [
          "a. Yes",
          "b. No",
          "c. Not applicable"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Yes",
        "id": 62
      },
      {
        "question": "Man is a cultural animal but ________ are not",
        "options": [
          "a. Levi-Straus",
          "b. Yawning",
          "c. Kroebar",
          "d. Animals"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Animals",
        "id": 63
      },
      {
        "question": "Energy theory of culture is called",
        "options": [
          "a. Determinological determinism",
          "b. Development determinism",
          "c. Pragmatic",
          "d. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Determinological determinism",
        "id": 64
      },
      {
        "question": "Biological theory of evolution was developed by",
        "options": [
          "a. Charles Davidism",
          "b. Sanderson",
          "c. Charles Dowellin",
          "d. Charles Darwin"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Charles Darwin",
        "id": 65
      },
      {
        "question": "Cultural history is based on core",
        "options": [
          "a. Norms and history",
          "b. Tradition and culture",
          "c. Values and tradition",
          "d. Tradition and folklores"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Values and tradition",
        "id": 66
      },
      {
        "question": "The country is reported to have sustained economic growth for a decade with annual GDP as at",
        "options": [
          "a. 6.1%",
          "b. 6.4%",
          "c. 6.2%",
          "d. 6.3%"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. 6.3%",
        "id": 67
      },
      {
        "question": "A common knowledge and point to note is that economic growth can occur",
        "options": [
          "a. Without development",
          "b. Without manufacturing",
          "c. With development",
          "d. With high GDP"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Without development",
        "id": 68
      },
      {
        "question": "The ultimate causes of all social change and political revolutions are to be sought",
        "options": [
          "a. In the minds of men",
          "b. In the increasing insight",
          "c. In truth and justice",
          "d. In change in mode of production"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. In change in mode of production",
        "id": 69
      },
      {
        "question": "In the traditional Nigerian economy, palm products represented",
        "options": [
          "a. A fixed method of the economy",
          "b. A mixed aspect of the economy",
          "c. A vital aspect of the economy",
          "d. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. A vital aspect of the economy",
        "id": 70
      },
      {
        "question": "The ecology and environment necessitated the fishing culture around the",
        "options": [
          "a. None Delta region",
          "b. Non-southern region",
          "c. Eastern region",
          "d. Delta region"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Delta region",
        "id": 71
      },
      {
        "question": "Production of agriculture in the traditional Nigerian economy was organized along",
        "options": [
          "a. Delta region",
          "b. Riverian region",
          "c. Lineage patterns",
          "d. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Riverian region",
        "id": 72
      },
      {
        "question": "The imperialistic undevelopment of Nigeria was instituted during trade with the _____",
        "options": [
          "a. East",
          "b. South",
          "c. North",
          "d. West"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. West",
        "id": 73
      },
      {
        "question": "The pre-colonial inter-group interaction among the various nationalities in Nigeria resulted in",
        "options": [
          "a. Cultural diffusion",
          "b. The well-beings of all the groups",
          "c. Political dominance",
          "d. A and C above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Cultural diffusion",
        "id": 74
      },
      {
        "question": "European trading activities on the Nigerian coast led to",
        "options": [
          "a. The abolition of slavery",
          "b. The displacement of the trans-Saharan trade route",
          "c. The evolution of territoriality",
          "d. The curtailment of African inter-group relations."
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. The displacement of the trans-Saharan trade route",
        "id": 75
      },
      {
        "question": "European imperialistic quest for the establishment of their trade and rule in Africa was heralded with the",
        "options": [
          "a. Battle of Lagos",
          "b. Battle of Legos",
          "c. Battle of the river Niger",
          "d. Battle of Jibowu"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Battle of Lagos",
        "id": 76
      },
      {
        "question": "The colonial master introduced wage labor to Nigeria to",
        "options": [
          "a. Check unemployment",
          "b. Ensure regular income",
          "c. Facilitate economic development",
          "d. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. All of the above",
        "id": 77
      },
      {
        "question": "The Luggardian policy of indirect rule in Nigeria was based on",
        "options": [
          "a. Control by treaty",
          "b. Control by negotiation",
          "c. Control by separation",
          "d. Control by force"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Control by negotiation",
        "special_instruction": "For questions 78 and 79, use the following passage:\n\nOn the 15th of October, 1904"
      },
      {
        "question": "Read the passage below and answer questions 78 and 79\n\nOn the 15th of October, 1904",
        "options": [],
        "id": 78
      },
      {
        "question": "The Lagos Youth Movement (source 1) made three demands of their",
        "options": [
          "a. The abolition of separate Chair demand",
          "b. An all-African Chair demand",
          "c. An all-African Chair demand",
          "d. The abolition of separate African representation",
          "e. The improvement of the status of Lagos"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. An all-African Chair demand",
        "id": 79
      },
      {
        "question": "In the struggle for independence, the __________ had earlier prepared the minds of the Nigerian political class.",
        "options": [
          "a. Lagos Youth Movement",
          "b. Lagosian Youth Movement",
          "c. Nigerian Youth Movement",
          "d. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Nigerian Youth Movement",
        "id": 80
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following countries is NOT a member of the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS)?",
        "options": [
          "a. Nigeria",
          "b. Ghana",
          "c. South Africa",
          "d. Senegal"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. South Africa",
        "id": 81
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the currency of Japan?",
        "options": [
          "a. Yen",
          "b. Won",
          "c. Ringgit",
          "d. Baht"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Yen",
        "id": 82
      },
      {
        "question": "Who is the author of the famous play 'Romeo and Juliet'?",
        "options": [
          "a. William Shakespeare",
          "b. Charles Dickens",
          "c. Jane Austen",
          "d. Mark Twain"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. William Shakespeare",
        "id": 83
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the capital city of Brazil?",
        "options": [
          "a. Buenos Aires",
          "b. Brasília",
          "c. Rio de Janeiro",
          "d. Santiago"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Brasília",
        "id": 84
      },
      {
        "question": "Which planet is known as the 'Red Planet'?",
        "options": [
          "a. Venus",
          "b. Mars",
          "c. Jupiter",
          "d. Saturn"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Mars",
        "id": 85
      },
      {
        "question": "Who painted the Mona Lisa?",
        "options": [
          "a. Vincent van Gogh",
          "b. Leonardo da Vinci",
          "c. Pablo Picasso",
          "d. Claude Monet"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Leonardo da Vinci",
        "id": 86
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the largest mammal in the world?",
        "options": [
          "a. Elephant",
          "b. Blue whale",
          "c. Giraffe",
          "d. Hippopotamus"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Blue whale",
        "id": 87
      },
      {
        "question": "Who wrote 'To Kill a Mockingbird'?",
        "options": [
          "a. J.K. Rowling",
          "b. Harper Lee",
          "c. George Orwell",
          "d. Ernest Hemingway"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Harper Lee",
        "id": 88
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the chemical symbol for the element gold?",
        "options": [
          "a. Au",
          "b. Ag",
          "c. Cu",
          "d. Fe"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Au",
        "id": 89
      },
      {
        "question": "Which country is known as the 'Land of the Rising Sun'?",
        "options": [
          "a. China",
          "b. Japan",
          "c. India",
          "d. South Korea"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Japan",
        "id": 90
      },
      {
        "question": "Who was the first President of the United States?",
        "options": [
          "a. Thomas Jefferson",
          "b. George Washington",
          "c. John Adams",
          "d. James Madison"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. George Washington",
        "id": 91
      },
      {
        "question": "In which year did World War II end?",
        "options": [
          "a. 1943",
          "b. 1944",
          "c. 1945",
          "d. 1946"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. 1945",
        "id": 92
      },
      {
        "question": "Who wrote 'Pride and Prejudice'?",
        "options": [
          "a. Jane Austen",
          "b. Charles Dickens",
          "c. Emily Brontë",
          "d. Charlotte Brontë"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Jane Austen",
        "id": 93
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the capital city of Canada?",
        "options": [
          "a. Vancouver",
          "b. Toronto",
          "c. Ottawa",
          "d. Montreal"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Ottawa",
        "id": 94
      },
      {
        "question": "Which river is the longest in the world?",
        "options": [
          "a. Amazon River",
          "b. Nile River",
          "c. Yangtze River",
          "d. Mississippi River"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Nile River",
        "id": 95
      },
      {
        "question": "Who invented the telephone?",
        "options": [
          "a. Alexander Graham Bell",
          "b. Thomas Edison",
          "c. Nikola Tesla",
          "d. Guglielmo Marconi"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Alexander Graham Bell",
        "id": 96
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the largest ocean on Earth?",
        "options": [
          "a. Atlantic Ocean",
          "b. Indian Ocean",
          "c. Southern Ocean",
          "d. Pacific Ocean"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Pacific Ocean",
        "id": 97
      },
      {
        "question": "Who is known as the 'Father of Computer Science'?",
        "options": [
          "a. Bill Gates",
          "b. Alan Turing",
          "c. Steve Jobs",
          "d. Mark Zuckerberg"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Alan Turing",
        "id": 98
      },
      {
        "question": "Which gas do plants absorb during photosynthesis?",
        "options": [
          "a. Oxygen",
          "b. Nitrogen",
          "c. Carbon Dioxide",
          "d. Hydrogen"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Carbon Dioxide",
        "id": 99
      },
      {
        "question": "Who wrote 'The Great Gatsby'?",
        "options": [
          "a. F. Scott Fitzgerald",
          "b. Ernest Hemingway",
          "c. J.D. Salinger",
          "d. William Faulkner"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. F. Scott Fitzgerald",
        "id": 100
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of this is not part of Egwurigwe's classification of culture regions",
        "options": [
          "a. Formal",
          "b. Functional",
          "c. Effective",
          "d. Perceptual",
          "e. Conceptual"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Effective",
        "id": 101
      },
      {
        "question": "Relations between farmers and herdsmen in Northern Nigerian can be described as",
        "options": [
          "a. Sedentary",
          "b. Systemic",
          "c. Transhumance",
          "d. all of the above",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Transhumance",
        "id": 102
      },
      {
        "question": "The indigenous Habei-Fulani type of administration is based on",
        "options": [
          "a. Village system",
          "b. The sultanate system",
          "c. The lineage system",
          "d. C and A",
          "e. A and B"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. The lineage system",
        "id": 103
      },
      {
        "question": "How many distinct cultural areas have been delineated in the cultural map of Nigerian?",
        "options": [
          "a. 20",
          "b. 10",
          "c. 40",
          "d. 15",
          "e. 35"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. 10",
        "id": 104
      },
      {
        "question": "The human environment is sub-divided into the following",
        "options": [
          "a. Physical and cultural",
          "b. Culture and state",
          "c. Atmosphere and rock",
          "d. Sand and clay",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Physical and cultural",
        "id": 105
      },
      {
        "question": "Tsav is a witchcraft portion for the god of",
        "options": [
          "a. Evil doer",
          "b. Ritual killers",
          "c. Tiv",
          "d. Witchcrafts",
          "e. Members"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "e. Members",
        "id": 106
      },
      {
        "question": "Because the nitty-gritty of cultural practices differs among humans, culture is",
        "options": [
          "a. Adaptive",
          "b. Shared",
          "c. Particularistic",
          "d. Learned",
          "e. Universalistic"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Particularistic",
        "id": 107
      },
      {
        "question": "Closely related to culture area is",
        "options": [
          "a. Formal culture",
          "b. Culture region",
          "c. Environment",
          "d. Education",
          "e. Ethnocentrism"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Culture region",
        "id": 108
      },
      {
        "question": "The physical environment consists of the following realms",
        "options": [
          "a. Hydrosphere, atmosphere, and lithosphere",
          "b. Abiotic and biotic",
          "c. Communal conflicts",
          "d. Ecology",
          "e. Political community"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Hydrosphere, atmosphere, and lithosphere",
        "id": 109
      },
      {
        "question": "Onige Otite in his fieldwork on cultural areas identified ethnic groups",
        "options": [
          "a. About 374",
          "b. 774",
          "c. About 250",
          "d. About 35",
          "e. About 500"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. About 374",
        "id": 110
      },
      {
        "question": "Perceptual culture region is a mental view of the people",
        "options": [
          "a. True",
          "b. False",
          "c. Both",
          "d. All",
          "e. None"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. True",
        "id": 111
      },
      {
        "question": "____ applied historical materialism in accounting for the origin of the state",
        "options": [
          "a. Socrates",
          "b. Max Weber",
          "c. Karl Marx",
          "d. Donald Trump",
          "e. Emile Durkheim"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Karl Marx",
        "id": 112
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a minority ethnic group in Nigeria",
        "options": [
          "a. Ikwerre",
          "b. Efik",
          "c. Ogba",
          "d. Hausa",
          "e. Ogoni"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Hausa",
        "id": 113
      },
      {
        "question": "Members of the Ekpe society who are said to act as messengers of the ancestors are called",
        "options": [
          "a. Egbo",
          "b. Ekan",
          "c. Amama",
          "d. Ikan",
          "e. Members"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Ikan",
        "id": 114
      },
      {
        "question": "Polyandrous family contrasts with polygamous family in that in the latter",
        "options": [
          "a. One man is married to one wife",
          "b. One woman is married to one man",
          "c. One woman is married to at least two men",
          "d. All the above",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. One man is married to one wife",
        "id": 115
      },
      {
        "question": "Ethnic minorities are different from the majority groups because of",
        "options": [
          "a. Religion",
          "b. Cultural tradition",
          "c. Lifestyle",
          "d. Language",
          "e. Ancestry"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Cultural tradition",
        "id": 116
      },
      {
        "question": "The art works of traditional Nigerian communities suggest that they are",
        "options": [
          "a. Magico-religious",
          "b. Scientists",
          "c. Disoriented artists",
          "d. Voodoo masters",
          "e. Preachers"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Magico-religious",
        "id": 117
      },
      {
        "question": "Colonial education proved an effective means of acculturation of _______",
        "options": [
          "a. Culture",
          "b. Environment",
          "c. People",
          "d. Subject",
          "e. Subject people"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. People",
        "id": 118
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these commodities was produced in pre-colonial Nigerian societies",
        "options": [
          "a. Gold",
          "b. Cement",
          "c. Petroleum",
          "d. Steel",
          "e. Platinum"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Gold",
        "id": 119
      },
      {
        "question": "The Negroes in South Africa can be classified as what group to white South Africans",
        "options": [
          "a. Subordinate group",
          "b. Super ordinate group",
          "c. Migrant group",
          "d. Ethnic pluralism",
          "e. Migrant super ordinate"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Subordinate group",
        "id": 120
      },
      {
        "question": "In levirate marriage, the biological father",
        "options": [
          "a. Owns the children of the marriage",
          "b. Children belong to the wife only",
          "c. Children belong to the deceased kinsman",
          "d. Children belong to the social fathers",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Children belong to the deceased kinsman",
        "id": 121
      },
      {
        "question": "The most important thing in Transhumance is that it is _________",
        "options": [
          "a. Seasonal",
          "b. Horizontal and vertical",
          "c. Annual",
          "d. Search for food",
          "e. Sedentary"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Seasonal",
        "id": 122
      },
      {
        "question": "The Ekpe-men are ranked in ________ for promotion",
        "options": [
          "a. 5-8 grades",
          "b. 7-10 grades",
          "c. 5-6 grades",
          "d. 7-9 grades",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. 7-9 grades",
        "id": 123
      },
      {
        "question": "The social importance attached to the highest rank of Ekpe cult is called",
        "options": [
          "a. Ekpe-logbo",
          "b. Egbo",
          "c. Ekong",
          "d. Uran",
          "e. Amama"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "e. Amama",
        "id": 124
      },
      {
        "question": "The view that the state guides individuals to realize the highest form of freedom is associated with",
        "options": [
          "a. Frederich Engels",
          "b. Angel Michael",
          "c. F.W. Hegel",
          "d. Karl Marx",
          "e. Max Weber"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. F.W. Hegel",
        "id": 125
      },
      {
        "question": "Sport the most appropriate statement from the following",
        "options": [
          "a. Human being revolves in culture",
          "b. People live in thatch houses",
          "c. Social life revolves around culture",
          "d. All of the above",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Social life revolves around culture",
        "id": 126
      },
      {
        "question": "Man's art, music, poetry have their roots in his",
        "options": [
          "a. Sub-culture",
          "b. Material culture",
          "c. Non-material culture",
          "d. Cultural diversity",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Material culture",
        "id": 127
      },
      {
        "question": "The analysis of land tenure focuses on the relationship based on",
        "options": [
          "a. Family",
          "b. Community",
          "c. Blood ties",
          "d. Farm land",
          "e. Men"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Farm land",
        "id": 128
      },
      {
        "question": "The cloth industry evolved into a sophisticated textile industry in West Africa by what year",
        "options": [
          "a. A.D 500",
          "b. B.C 70",
          "c. A.D 2000",
          "d. A.D 1000",
          "e. B.C. 2000"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. A.D 500",
        "id": 129
      },
      {
        "question": "A form of discrimination arising from the normal functioning of society refers to",
        "options": [
          "a. Institutional discrimination",
          "b. Group interaction",
          "c. Integration",
          "d. Ethnic pluralism",
          "e. Attitudinal discrimination"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Institutional discrimination",
        "id": 130
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these health problems does traditional medicine in Nigeria compete favorably with orthodox medicine",
        "options": [
          "a. HIV/AIDS",
          "b. Surgery",
          "c. Orthopedics",
          "d. Malaria",
          "e. Cancer"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Surgery",
        "id": 131
      },
      {
        "question": "Abiotic components consist of one of the following elements",
        "options": [
          "a. Lithosphere",
          "b. Earth",
          "c. Water",
          "d. Air",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Lithosphere",
        "id": 132
      },
      {
        "question": "Acculturation refers to acquiring",
        "options": [
          "a. Superior culture",
          "b. Everybody culture",
          "c. Good culture only",
          "d. None of the above",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Everybody culture",
        "id": 133
      },
      {
        "question": "The Mbatsav is the highest traditional political council found among the",
        "options": [
          "a. Ogoni",
          "b. Idoma",
          "c. Tiv",
          "d. Nupe",
          "e. Benin"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Tiv",
        "id": 134
      },
      {
        "question": "The belief that sick persons are possessed by demons is known as",
        "options": [
          "a. Evil attack",
          "b. Demonology",
          "c. Spiritualism",
          "d. Marine spirit",
          "e. Deliverance"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Demonology",
        "id": 135
      },
      {
        "question": "Traditional political system of Northern Nigeria could be described as",
        "options": [
          "a. Theocratic",
          "b. Secularistic",
          "c. Democratic",
          "d. None of the above",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Democratic",
        "id": 136
      },
      {
        "question": "Cultural relativism supports",
        "options": [
          "a. Ethnocentrism",
          "b. Anti-religion",
          "c. Culture shock",
          "d. Inhuman practices",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Culture shock",
        "id": 137
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these is the major reason for the study of the courses Nigerian Peoples and Culture",
        "options": [
          "a. To promote tribal hegemony",
          "b. To promote social exclusion",
          "c. To promote unity",
          "d. None of the above",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. To promote unity",
        "id": 138
      },
      {
        "question": "Culture is not an important factor in disease and illness determination",
        "options": [
          "a. Yes",
          "b. No",
          "c. A and B",
          "d. None",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. No",
        "id": 139
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is the odd one",
        "options": [
          "a. Language",
          "b. Ancestry",
          "c. National origin",
          "d. Culture",
          "e. Prejudice"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Culture",
        "id": 140
      },
      {
        "question": "The form of marriage in which a kinsman takes over the wife of deceased kin is known as",
        "options": [
          "a. Levirate",
          "b. Pawn",
          "c. Woman-to-woman",
          "d. None",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Levirate",
        "id": 141
      },
      {
        "question": "Traditional health practices are grouped into any of the following",
        "options": [
          "a. Deities and spiritual forces",
          "b. Roots and herbs",
          "c. Sorcery and mystics",
          "d. Natural and supernatural",
          "e. All the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Natural and supernatural",
        "id": 142
      },
      {
        "question": "In Yoruba Kingdom, the most senior chiefs gather at",
        "options": [
          "a. King's palace",
          "b. Town Hall",
          "c. Oba's Palace",
          "d. Senior chiefs, Palace",
          "e. Meeting place"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Oba's Palace",
        "id": 143
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these forms of marriage is the practice of marriage a wife for a deceased relation in which the woman's children belonged to the deceased husband",
        "options": [
          "a. Sororate",
          "b. Gift",
          "c. Ghost",
          "d. All of the above",
          "e. None"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Ghost",
        "id": 144
      },
      {
        "question": "Social stratification means",
        "options": [
          "a. Social progress",
          "b. Social deprivation",
          "c. Social inequality",
          "d. Social equity",
          "e. None"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Social inequality",
        "id": 145
      },
      {
        "question": "In centralized societies, social mobility is",
        "options": [
          "a. Accessible",
          "b. Fixed",
          "c. Flexible",
          "d. Rigid",
          "e. None"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Rigid",
        "id": 146
      },
      {
        "question": "The NOK culture is said to have flourished between",
        "options": [
          "a. 1800-1900",
          "b. 900-500 BC",
          "c. 1960-200",
          "d. None of the above",
          "e. None"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. 900-500 BC",
        "id": 147
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these concepts-",
        "options": [
          "a. polygon",
          "b. Polygamy",
          "c. Bigamy",
          "d. Polyandry"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Bigamy",
        "id": 149
      },
      {
        "question": "Minority status exists when one group imposes, upon another",
        "options": [
          "a. Prejudice",
          "b. Discrimination",
          "c. Stratification",
          "d. Power",
          "e. Imposition"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Power",
        "id": 150
      },
      {
        "question": "The etiology of disease can be explored in areas of",
        "options": [
          "a. Science",
          "b. Witchcraft",
          "c. socio-culture",
          "d. Biology",
          "e. Medical disease"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. socio-culture",
        "id": 151
      },
      {
        "question": "Rights of passage involves separation, transition, and",
        "options": [
          "a. Divination",
          "b. Pre-interment",
          "c. Rituals",
          "d. Re-incarnation",
          "e. Re-incorporation"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "e. Re-incorporation",
        "id": 152
      },
      {
        "question": "The ancient NOK people lived in what part of Nigeria",
        "options": [
          "a. Cross River",
          "b. Akwaibom",
          "c. Plateau",
          "d. Oyo",
          "e. Igbo-Ukwu"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Plateau",
        "id": 153
      },
      {
        "question": "The indigenous system of health care is based on personal",
        "options": [
          "a. Knowledge and strength",
          "b. Roots and Herbs",
          "c. Experience and observations",
          "d. Priest and divination"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Roots and Herbs",
        "id": 154
      },
      {
        "question": "The second stage in personality development to Freud after child birth is",
        "options": [
          "a. Anal stage",
          "b. Phalic stage",
          "c. Freudian stage",
          "d. oral"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Anal stage",
        "id": 155
      },
      {
        "question": "Islam is a religion that has no regard for education",
        "options": [
          "a. True",
          "b. False",
          "c. Both"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. False",
        "id": 156
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these is an advantage of indigenous health care?",
        "options": [
          "a. It cures Hiv/Aids",
          "b. It is comprehensive",
          "c. It disorganizes wicked spirits",
          "d. It disregards bacteria",
          "e. It is for deliverance"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. It is comprehensive",
        "id": 157
      },
      {
        "question": "Group solidarity or morale is one of the consequences of",
        "options": [
          "a. Stratification",
          "b. Prejudice",
          "c. Class",
          "d. Bekuef"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Stratification",
        "id": 158
      },
      {
        "question": "The process of acculturation begins with the development of common",
        "options": [
          "a. Goal",
          "b. History",
          "c. Language",
          "d. Culture",
          "e. Accent"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Language",
        "id": 159
      },
      {
        "question": "Nigeria is said to have the following number of ethic and linguistic.",
        "options": [
          "a. About 20",
          "b. About 30",
          "c. About 150",
          "d. About 25",
          "e. About 350"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. About 25",
        "id": 160
      },
      {
        "question": "The type of family involving the marriage of one woman to more than one husband is known as -------",
        "options": [
          "a. Pomography",
          "b. Polygamy",
          "c. Polyandrous",
          "d. All of the above",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Polyandrous",
        "id": 161
      },
      {
        "question": "Lineage land tenure is practiced by the",
        "options": [
          "a. kulabaris",
          "b. Ijaws",
          "c. Ogonis",
          "d. Tivs",
          "e. Awaris in Nigeria"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Ijaws",
        "id": 162
      },
      {
        "question": "The religions institution designed to solicit the help of the water spirits through invocation, sacrifices and dramatic representation of spirits in masquerades is commonly practiced amongst the. ------------",
        "options": [
          "a. Ogonis",
          "b. Ikwerres",
          "c. Kalabaris",
          "d. Igallas",
          "e. Igberies"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Kalabaris",
        "id": 163
      },
      {
        "question": "Ekpe is a secret society flourishing chiefly among the",
        "options": [
          "a. Noks",
          "b. Ekpes",
          "c. Efiks",
          "d. Nupes",
          "e. Urhobos"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Efiks",
        "id": 164
      },
      {
        "question": "Spirit can be classified separately from divinities and ancestors",
        "options": [
          "a. True",
          "b. False",
          "c. Both"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. True",
        "id": 165
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is the centre of Igbo traditional priesthood.",
        "options": [
          "a. Eri",
          "b. Ori",
          "c. Nri",
          "d. Obi",
          "e. Ada"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Ori",
        "id": 166
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is the most common totem animal in Rivers State.",
        "options": [
          "a. Tortoise",
          "b. Vulture",
          "c. Pigeon",
          "d. Python",
          "e. Rabbit"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Python",
        "id": 167
      },
      {
        "question": "The issue of states creation in Nigerian could be traced to the political leaders from the ____",
        "options": [
          "a. North",
          "b. South",
          "c. East",
          "d. West",
          "e. Middle Belt"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. North",
        "id": 168
      },
      {
        "question": "The rituals associated with birth commence with",
        "options": [
          "a. Child birth",
          "b. Naming ceremony",
          "c. Pregnancy",
          "d. Initiation",
          "e. Rites"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Naming ceremony",
        "id": 169
      },
      {
        "question": "Some aspects of culture are more prone to change than others",
        "options": [
          "a. True",
          "b. False",
          "c. None"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. True",
        "id": 170
      },
      {
        "question": "_______ argues that the contradictions in the mode of production, at a certain historical juncture, translate into antagonistic class relations",
        "options": [
          "a. Herbert Spencer",
          "b. Frederica Engels",
          "c. Max Weber",
          "d. Karl Marx",
          "e. Emile Durkheim"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Karl Marx",
        "id": 171
      },
      {
        "question": "The colony of Lagos was ceded to the British as a crown colony in",
        "options": [
          "a. 1950",
          "b. 1862",
          "c. 1808",
          "d. 1896",
          "e. 1904"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. 1862",
        "id": 172
      },
      {
        "question": "Under the communal mode of production, social organization centered around",
        "options": [
          "a. family system",
          "b. groups",
          "c. communities",
          "d. organizations"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. family system",
        "id": 173
      },
      {
        "question": "In Benin, guilds of a very restricted caste type controlled the famous",
        "options": [
          "a. Class and bead industry",
          "b. Clay and granite industry",
          "c. Brass and bronze industry",
          "d. Mining and iron industry"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Brass and bronze industry",
        "id": 174
      },
      {
        "question": "The artwork of life is dated between",
        "options": [
          "a. 10th and 12th centuries",
          "b. 11th and 15th centuries",
          "c. 16th century",
          "d. 14th and 17th centuries"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. 11th and 15th centuries",
        "id": 175
      },
      {
        "question": "_________ is a set of practices and beliefs of a group in relation to a local god.",
        "options": [
          "a. Cult",
          "b. Religion",
          "c. Organization",
          "d. Sect"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Cult",
        "id": 176
      },
      {
        "question": "____________ defined religion as a unified system of beliefs and practices relative to sacred things.",
        "options": [
          "a. Joseph-Obi",
          "b. Ogbanga",
          "c. Durkheim",
          "d. Auguste",
          "e. Onwueiogwu"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Durkheim",
        "id": 177
      },
      {
        "question": "Among the Ikwerre people, God is called__________",
        "options": [
          "a. Oluwa",
          "b. Baba",
          "c. Chiokike",
          "d. Abasi",
          "e. chukwu"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Chiokike",
        "id": 178
      },
      {
        "question": "The book 'The Protestant Ethic and the Spirit of Capitalism' was written by _______",
        "options": [
          "a. Karl Marx",
          "b. Bishop Oyedepo",
          "c. Pastor Adeboye",
          "d. Max Weber",
          "e. Pastor Kumuyi"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. Max Weber",
        "id": 179
      },
      {
        "question": "Every religious practice in Niger engages in special _______",
        "options": [
          "a. Oath taking",
          "b. Ceremonies",
          "c. Assignment",
          "d. Tradition",
          "e. Assembly"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Ceremonies",
        "id": 180
      },
      {
        "question": "__________ religion is associated with ancestor worship in Nigeria.",
        "options": [
          "a. Islam",
          "b. Christianity",
          "c. African Traditional Religion",
          "d. Catholic",
          "e. Hindu"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. African Traditional Religion",
        "id": 181
      },
      {
        "question": "______________ is a small evangelical group that recruits its members by conversion and adopts a radical stance toward the state and society.",
        "options": [
          "a. Sect",
          "b. Cult",
          "c. Church",
          "d. Club",
          "e. Occult"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Cult",
        "id": 182
      },
      {
        "question": "__________ defined religion as consisting of ideas and values produced by human beings in the course of their development?",
        "options": [
          "a. Giddens",
          "b. Feuerbach",
          "c. Agwanwo",
          "d. Worlu",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Feuerbach",
        "id": 183
      },
      {
        "question": "The Orthodox Church includes which one of the followings?",
        "options": [
          "a. Roman Catholic, Anglican and Methodist",
          "b. Anglican, Assemblies and 0.0.0.",
          "c. Methodist, Anglican and Cherubim",
          "d. Roman Catholic, Methodist and R.C.C.G.",
          "e. Christ Embassy, Winners & Redeemed"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Roman Catholic, Anglican and Methodist",
        "id": 184
      },
      {
        "question": "Religion has _____________",
        "options": [
          "a. No impact on development",
          "b. Was founded by Max Weber",
          "c. Has a huge impact on development",
          "d. Is only practiced by Nigerians",
          "e. Is not a universal concern"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Has a huge impact on development",
        "id": 185
      },
      {
        "question": "Religion has only_________definition",
        "options": [
          "a. One",
          "b. Two definitions",
          "c. Three types",
          "d. None",
          "e. Several"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "e. Several",
        "id": 186
      },
      {
        "question": "Religion can be broadly defined as",
        "options": [
          "a. The system of belief imbued with tradition",
          "b. Any system of belief that is imbued with sacredness",
          "c. Some system of belief mixed with tradition and culture",
          "d. Disorganized system of belief and practices resting on faith",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Any system of belief that is imbued with sacredness",
        "id": 187
      },
      {
        "question": "_______ defined religion as 'a unified system of belief and practices relative to things set apart and forbidden....'",
        "options": [
          "a. Levine and Spates",
          "b. Emile Durkheim",
          "c. Talkot Parson",
          "d. Karl Marx",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Emile Durkheim",
        "id": 188
      },
      {
        "question": "According to Berger, one of the most important aspects of religion is its ability to:",
        "options": [
          "a. Explain such phenomena as evil, suffering, and death",
          "b. Highlight wrongs and rights in society",
          "c. Make people decide on heaven or hell",
          "d. Judge the world",
          "e. Die and rise again"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Explain such phenomena as evil, suffering, and death",
        "id": 189
      },
      {
        "question": "Religion cannot be appropriately interpreted by mere observation because it is _______",
        "options": [
          "a. Erratic",
          "b. Symbolic",
          "c. Spiritual",
          "d. Indepth",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Symbolic",
        "id": 190
      },
      {
        "question": "According to Otite and Oginwo (1979), man's relationship to the supernatural is",
        "options": [
          "a. Disorganized",
          "b. Ordered and not haphazard",
          "c. Ordered and Haphazard",
          "d. Visibly evident",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Ordered and not haphazard",
        "id": 191
      },
      {
        "question": "To many Nigerians, God is real but transcendental, remote in their day-to-day lives but deserves ________",
        "options": [
          "a. Sacrifice",
          "b. Worship",
          "c. Peace",
          "d. Accolades",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Worship",
        "id": 192
      },
      {
        "question": "In practice, God is seen as _______",
        "options": [
          "a. Immanent, only powerful and omnipresent",
          "b. Dispenser of final justice",
          "c. One whose final decision cannot be changed",
          "d. All of the above",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. All of the above",
        "id": 193
      },
      {
        "question": "Like most African societies, Nigerian traditional societies",
        "options": [
          "a. Believe in his existence and place him at the apex above all others",
          "b. Agree that he is not indispensable",
          "c. Agree that he is spiritual and unreal",
          "d. All of the above",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. All of the above",
        "id": 194
      },
      {
        "question": "Ogoni call God _______",
        "options": [
          "a. Barisila",
          "b. Bhari",
          "c. Bari",
          "d. Gbene mene",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Bari",
        "id": 195
      },
      {
        "question": "Ogoni view God as",
        "options": [
          "a. A female who has productive powers",
          "b. A man who has a multitude of children",
          "c. A child of impeccable character",
          "d. All of the above",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. A female who has productive powers",
        "id": 196
      },
      {
        "question": "The Ogba People call God:",
        "options": [
          "a. Chukwudibia",
          "b. Chukwubiama",
          "c. Chukwuabiama",
          "d. Chukwudi",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Chukwubiama",
        "id": 197
      },
      {
        "question": "All these are names of God in various languages except",
        "options": [
          "a. Ebilikpabi",
          "b. Chineke",
          "c. Allah",
          "d. Tamuno",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "e. All of the above",
        "id": 198
      },
      {
        "question": "There are three religious Specialists in Igbo Tradition. These are",
        "options": [
          "a. Priest, mediator between men and divinities",
          "b. Priest, Diviners and medicine man",
          "c. Priest, medicine man and Chukwu",
          "d. Diviners, Priest and Arochukwu",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Priest, mediator between men and divinities",
        "id": 199
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is the most Correct?",
        "options": [
          "a. Though culturally diverse, most Nigerian religious beliefs share many things in common",
          "b. Divinities are derived from deities",
          "c. Divinities act as intermediaries between deities and men",
          "d. All of the above",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. All of the above",
        "id": 200
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these names does not refer to a Yoruba deity?",
        "options": [
          "a. Orisa",
          "b. Ifa",
          "c. Esu",
          "d. Obatala",
          "e. C and D above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "e. C and D above",
        "id": 201
      },
      {
        "question": "The following are classified as spirits EXCEPT ________",
        "options": [
          "a. Ogbanje",
          "b. Abiku",
          "c. Oru",
          "d. All of the above",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. All of the above",
        "id": 202
      },
      {
        "question": "______________ viewed religion as the Opium of the masses and means employed by the ruling class to maintain hold on the poor",
        "options": [
          "a. Emile Durkheim",
          "b. Karl Marx",
          "c. Sigmund Freud",
          "d. None of the above",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Karl Marx",
        "id": 203
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is more correct between Marx's and Durkheim's view of religion?",
        "options": [
          "a. Marx sees religion as imposing",
          "b. Durkheim supports Marx in seeing religion as a tool for oppression",
          "c. Durkheim sees religion as necessary for survival",
          "d. Weber looked at its difficulty in causing social change",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Durkheim sees religion as necessary for survival",
        "id": 204
      },
      {
        "question": "To Sigmund Freud, religion is:",
        "options": [
          "a. An evidence of infantile behavior",
          "b. A means of social cohesion",
          "c. A tool to stir up great social upheaval",
          "d. A tool for reconciliation",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. An evidence of infantile behavior",
        "id": 205
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of this current activity supports Weber's Claims?",
        "options": [
          "a. Tremendous social change due to the advent of Islam",
          "b. Tremendous social change due to the advent of Christianity",
          "c. Modern Nigerian experience of religious Conflict",
          "d. Increased unrest in society",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "e. All of the above",
        "id": 206
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is the most correct statement?",
        "options": [
          "a. The diffused nature of religion and politics in the past also gave tremendous opportunity to the privileged to manipulate and advance their cause to the detriment of the poor",
          "b. The diffused nature of religion and politics in the past also gave tremendous opportunity to the underprivileged to manipulate and advance their cause to the detriment of the rich",
          "c. The diffused nature of religion and politics in the past also gave tremendous opportunity to the underprivileged to manipulate and advance their cause to the detriment of the poor",
          "d. The diffused nature of religion and politics in the past does not give tremendous opportunity to the privileged to manipulate and advance their cause to the detriment of the poor",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. The diffused nature of religion and politics in the past also gave tremendous opportunity to the privileged to manipulate and advance their cause to the detriment of the poor",
        "id": 207
      },
      {
        "question": "Is there any link between religion and political, economic and social life in Nigeria?",
        "options": [
          "a. Yes",
          "b. No",
          "c. Sometimes",
          "d. None of the above",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Yes",
        "id": 208
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of this is not identified as a cult",
        "options": [
          "a. Ogboni",
          "b. Sango",
          "c. Ekpe",
          "d. All of the above",
          "e. None of the above+"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. All of the above",
        "id": 209
      },
      {
        "question": "The basic objective of adult men being organized into secret societies that imitated the activity of the spirits was to maintain _________",
        "options": [
          "a. Religious affiliation",
          "b. Moral Order",
          "c. Status",
          "d. Numerical strength",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Moral Order",
        "id": 210
      },
      {
        "question": "In which tribe do we have religious people soliciting for the help of the water spirits through invocation, dancing, and sacrifices?",
        "options": [
          "a. Ekine Society",
          "b. Igbo",
          "c. Yoruba",
          "d. Efik",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Ekine Society",
        "id": 211
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is the most appropriate statement? Egbo is ________",
        "options": [
          "a. A mysterious spirit who is supposed to live in the river and to preside at ceremonies of a society",
          "b. A mysterious spirit who is supposed to live in the jungle and to preside at ceremonies of a society",
          "c. A mysterious spirit who is supposed to live in the air and to preside at ceremonies of a society",
          "d. All of the above",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. A mysterious spirit who is supposed to live in the jungle and to preside at ceremonies of a society",
        "id": 212
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of this is true of the Ekpe Group?",
        "options": [
          "a. Only males can join",
          "b. Boys are initiated at about the age of puberty",
          "c. Members are bound by an oath of secrecy",
          "d. Fees on entrance are payable",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "e. All of the above",
        "id": 213
      },
      {
        "question": "The highest rank of the Ekpe is",
        "options": [
          "a. Nsibidi",
          "b. Amama",
          "c. Ikan",
          "d. Ekong",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Nsibidi",
        "id": 214
      },
      {
        "question": "Worship, prayers, and sacrifices in Nigeria were means of ________",
        "options": [
          "a. Creating crises",
          "b. Creating harmonious relationships among the people",
          "c. Creating untouchable relationships between people and God",
          "d. All of the above",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. All of the above",
        "id": 215
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these is not among the four objectives of Sacrifice?",
        "options": [
          "a. Expiation",
          "b. Warding of molestation from Unknown spirit",
          "c. Mayhem",
          "d. Petition",
          "e. Thanksgiving"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c. Mayhem",
        "id": 216
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these are not among the key factors that influenced the decline of indigenous religion?",
        "options": [
          "a. Slave trade",
          "b. Indentured labor",
          "c. Colonialism",
          "d. Christianity",
          "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Indentured labor",
        "id": 217
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of this led to the decline of indigenous religion in the face of Islam?",
        "options": [
        "a. Conversion",
        "b. Conquest",
        "c. Colonization",
        "d. Missionary activities",
        "e. None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b. Conquest",
        "id": 218
      },
      {
        "question": "The search for a Supreme Being like Anyanwu is a characteristic feature of_________",
        "options": [
          "a. Monotheism",
          "b. Polytheism",
          "c. Hinduism",
          "d. African Traditional Religion",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. Monotheism",
        "id": 219
      },
      {
        "question": "The emphasis on rituals, spirits, and communication with the supernatural are characteristics of _______",
        "options": [
          "a. Monotheism",
          "b. Polytheism",
          "c. Hinduism",
          "d. African Traditional Religion",
          "e. All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d. African Traditional Religion",
        "id": 220
      },
      {
        "question": "The suppression of indigenous religious practices by colonial authorities contributed to the decline of indigenous religion. True/False?",
        "options": [
          "a. True",
          "b. False"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a. True",
        "id": 221
      }, {
        "question": "Which one of these is a theophoric name?",
        "options": [
          "a) Kayode",
          "b) Tokunboh",
          "c) Rashidi",
          "d) Ogunde",
          "e) Kekere"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d) Ogunde",
        "id": 122
      },
      {
        "question": "The first case of HIV/AIDS in Nigeria was diagnosed in?",
        "options": [
          "a) 1980",
          "b) 1983",
          "c) 1990",
          "d) 1986",
          "e) 1989"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d) 1986",
        "id": 123
      },
      {
        "question": "In Yoruba kingdom, the most senior chiefs gathered at?",
        "options": [
          "a) Town hall",
          "b) Oba's house",
          "c) King's palace",
          "d) Senior chiefs palace",
          "e) All of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c) King's palace",
        "id": 124
      },
      {
        "question": "How many distinct cultural areas have been delineated in the cultural map of Nigeria?",
        "options": [
          "a) 20",
          "b) 40",
          "c) 15",
          "d) 35",
          "e) 10"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "e) 10",
        "id": 125
      },
      {
        "question": "Closely related to culture area is?",
        "options": [
          "a) Formal culture",
          "b) Culture region",
          "c) Environment",
          "d) Education",
          "e) Ethnocentrism"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b) Culture region",
        "id": 126
      },
      {
        "question": "In what decent system do individuals acquire membership in both patrilineal and matrilineal groups according to culturally determined rules?",
        "options": [
          "a) Ambilineal",
          "b) Unilineal",
          "c) Matrilineal",
          "d) Polylineal",
          "e) Double descent"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "e) Double descent",
        "id": 127
      },
      {
        "question": "An ecosystem refers to?",
        "options": [
          "a) Community and its habitat",
          "b) Plant and animal population",
          "c) Economy and population",
          "d) An assemblage of organisms"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a) Community and its habitat",
        "id": 128
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the smallest component of culture?",
        "options": [
          "a) Units",
          "b) Traits",
          "c) Areas",
          "d) Regions",
          "e) Institutions"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b) Traits",
        "id": 129
      },
      {
        "question": "When a couple lives in their own house, what is the pattern called?",
        "options": [
          "a) Natalocal",
          "b) Neolocal",
          "c) Uzorlocal",
          "d) Unilocal"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a) Natalocal",
        "id": 130
      },
      {
        "question": "Rites of passage involve separation, transition, and what else?",
        "options": [
          "a) Incarceration",
          "b) Incorporation",
          "c) Transformation",
          "d) Re-incorporation"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d) Re-incorporation",
        "id": 131
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the most dominant economic activity in Nigeria since ancient times?",
        "options": [
          "a) Cloth making",
          "b) Agriculture",
          "c) Blacksmithing",
          "d) Mining",
          "e) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b) Agriculture",
        "id": 132
      },
      {
        "question": "Who looked at religion as having the potential for causing social change and for stirring up social upheaval?",
        "options": [
          "a) Karl Marx",
          "b) Talcott Persons",
          "c) Marx Weber",
          "d) Emile Durkheim"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c) Marx Weber",
        "id": 133
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these is notable for acephalous and highly fragmented political structure?",
        "options": [
          "a) Igbo",
          "b) Kanem-Bornu",
          "c) Igala",
          "d) Yoruba",
          "e) Hausa/Fulani"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a) Igbo",
        "id": 134
      },
      {
        "question": "World Aids day is?",
        "options": [
          "a) December 1",
          "b) July 10",
          "c) January 6",
          "d) September 4"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a) December 1",
        "id": 135
      },
      {
        "question": "Which ethnic group uses the hakimi to administer the district?",
        "options": [
          "a) Yoruba",
          "b) Igbo",
          "c) Hausa/Fulani",
          "d) Tiv",
          "e) Idoma"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c) Hausa/Fulani",
        "id": 136
      },
      {
        "question": "Which word best describes a people's worldview?",
        "options": [
          "a) Relativism",
          "b) Cosmology",
          "c) Universe",
          "d) Reincarnation"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b) Cosmology",
        "id": 137
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these practices marriage by elopement?",
        "options": [
          "a) Andoni",
          "b) Tiv",
          "c) Benin",
          "d) Iriebe"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b) Tiv",
        "id": 138
      },
      {
        "question": "Which term best describes the marriage of a man to more than one wife?",
        "options": [
          "a) Serial monogamy",
          "b) Polygamy",
          "c) Adultery",
          "d) Polyandry"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b) Polygamy",
        "id": 139
      },
      {
        "question": "______ regulate human behavior and are standards for action in society?",
        "options": [
          "a) Values",
          "b) Cosmology",
          "c) Norm",
          "d) Rites of sage",
          "e) Institution"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c) Norm",
        "id": 140
      },
      {
        "question": "The estimated number of ethnic groups in Nigeria is?",
        "options": [
          "a) 150",
          "b) 250 and more",
          "c) 12,000",
          "d) 40",
          "e) 10"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b) 250 and more",
        "id": 141
      },
      {
        "question": "An Oba's judicial decision was enforced by the age grades called?",
        "options": [
          "a) Elegbe",
          "b) Ogboni",
          "c) Baale",
          "d) Sango",
          "e) Ife"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a) Elegbe",
        "id": 142
      },
      {
        "question": "The mechanism by which land is made available to cultivators is called?",
        "options": [
          "a) Fallow system",
          "b) Land tenure",
          "c) Land acquisition",
          "d) Occupancy right"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b) Land tenure",
        "id": 143
      },
      {
        "question": "These are cultural impediments in the control of HIV/AIDS in Nigeria except?",
        "options": [
          "a) Polygamy",
          "b) Early marriage",
          "c) Disinheritance of widows",
          "d) Ignorance and myths",
          "e) Sacrifices"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "e) Sacrifices",
        "id": 144
      },
      {
        "question": "____ is a socio-historical concept and embodiment of culture and an invention for adaptation to the environment?",
        "options": [
          "a) Heritage",
          "b) Cosmology",
          "c) Culture",
          "d) Symbol"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a) Heritage",
        "id": 145
      },
      {
        "question": "Colonization involves all but?",
        "options": [
          "a) Economic exploitation",
          "b) Political marginalization",
          "c) Social disorganization",
          "d) Distortion of history",
          "e) Equity"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "e) Equity",
        "id": 146
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the agency responsible for the coordination of national HIV/AIDS called?",
        "options": [
          "a) UNICEF",
          "b) UNESCO",
          "c) ACTION AIDS",
          "d) NACA"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d) NACA",
        "id": 147
      },
      {
        "question": "The transformation of raw material into finished goods belongs to _____ sector of the economy?",
        "options": [
          "a) Primary",
          "b) Secondary",
          "c) Tertiary",
          "d) Nursery and pre-primary"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b) Secondary",
        "id": 148
      },
      {
        "question": "The universally accepted beginning of a family is?",
        "options": [
          "a) Marriage",
          "b) Child birth",
          "c) Building a family home",
          "d) Knowing one's kindred"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a) Marriage",
        "id": 149
      },
      {
        "question": "Those who think that their culture is more superior to others are?",
        "options": [
          "a) Ethnologistic",
          "b) Ethnocentric",
          "c) Senocentric",
          "d) Malinocentric",
          "e) Culturecentric"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b) Ethnocentric",
        "id": 150
      },
      {
        "question": "Pick the odd one out?",
        "options": [
          "a) Norms",
          "b) Values",
          "c) Customs",
          "d) Kinship",
          "e) Belief"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d) Kinship",
        "id": 151
      },
      {
        "question": "Before the end of 15 beads for gold to the?",
        "options": [
          "a) Nok",
          "b) Igbo-ukwu",
          "c) Ife",
          "d) Benin",
          "e) Hausa"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d) Benin",
        "id": 152
      },
      {
        "question": "The act of a smaller culture that rejects the dominant culture is?",
        "options": [
          "a) Counter-culture",
          "b) Cultural relativism",
          "c) Subculture",
          "d) Mock culture",
          "e) Intra-culture"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a) Counter-culture",
        "id": 153
      },
      {
        "question": "_____ infections attack people whose immune system has been badly compromised?",
        "options": [
          "a) Vigorous",
          "b) Opportunistic",
          "c) Syndrome",
          "d) Immune deficiency",
          "e) Immune"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b) Opportunistic",
        "id": 154
      },
      {
        "question": "Pick the odd one out?",
        "options": [
          "a) Lake",
          "b) Island",
          "c) Rivers",
          "d) Seas"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b) Island",
        "id": 155
      },
      {
        "question": "Nigeria is a ________ creation?",
        "options": [
          "a) Colonial",
          "b) Post-colonial",
          "c) Pre-colonial",
          "d) None of the above"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "a) Colonial",
        "id": 156
      },
      {
        "question": "In centralized societies, social mobility is?",
        "options": [
          "a) Accessible",
          "b) Fixed",
          "c) Flexible",
          "d) Social equity",
          "e) Impossible"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "b) Fixed",
        "id": 157
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these health problems does traditional medicine in Nigeria compete favorably with orthodox medicine?",
        "options": [
          "a) HIV/AIDS",
          "b) Surgery",
          "c) Orthopedics",
          "d) Cancer",
          "e) Heart transplant"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c) Orthopedics",
        "id": 158
      },
      {
        "question": "Among the Ibos, the born-to-die child is infested with the spirit of?",
        "options": [
          "a) Obiarije",
          "b) Odanje",
          "c) Ogbanje",
          "d) Ochanja"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "c) Ogbanje",
        "id": 159
      },
      {
        "question": "Orisa is worshipped among ______ people?",
        "options": [
          "a) Igbo",
          "b) Fulani",
          "c) Hausa",
          "d) Yoruba"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d) Yoruba",
        "id": 160
      },
      {
        "question": "____ carried out a Jihad in Northern Nigeria?",
        "options": [
          "a) Ahmadu Bello",
          "b) Tafawa Belewa",
          "c) Gali Naaba",
          "d) Usman Dan Fodio"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "d) Usman Dan Fodio",
        "id": 161
      }

    ]
  }
  